Finding Aid for the Paul B. MacCready Papers, 1931-2002 MacCreadyPB
California Institute of Technology Archives and Special Collections
- Writings and talks, 4
  - Writings, 1
    - Animal-powered flight, Free Flight Vol. XVIII, No. 4, 1984 April; MacCreadyPB_04_01_006_15 (Box 4.6, Folder 15)
    - Soaring aerodynamics of frigate birds, Soaring Vol. 48, No. 7, 1984 July; MacCreadyPB_04_01_006_16 (Box 4.6, Folder 16)
    - QN- the time traveler, National Air and Space Museum Research Report, 1985; MacCreadyPB_04_01_007_01 (Box 4.7, Folder 1)
    - Long endurance aircraft performance, Unmanned Systems Vol. 4, No. 1, 1985 Summer; MacCreadyPB_04_01_007_02 (Box 4.7, Folder 2)
    - Gossamer aircraft, and frontiers in thinking, 1985 June 7; MacCreadyPB_04_01_007_03 (Box 4.7, Folder 3)
    - Potential for the evolution of a new species, Bicycling Magazine, 1985 July; MacCreadyPB_04_01_007_04 (Box 4.7, Folder 4)
    - Bionic Bat: stored energy human powered speed aircraft, AIAA/SAE/ASME/ASEE 21st joint propulsion conference, 1985 July 8-10; MacCreadyPB_04_01_007_05 (Box 4.7, Folder 5)
    - Development of a wing-flapping flying replica of the largest Pterosaur, AIAA/SAE/ASME/ASEE 21st joint propulsion conference, 1985 July 8-10; MacCreadyPB_04_01_007_06 (Box 4.7, Folder 6)
    - Natural and artificial flying machines, Technical Soaring Vol. 9, No. 3, 1985 September; MacCreadyPB_04_01_007_07 (Box 4.7, Folder 7)
    - The great pterodactyl project, Engineering & Science Vol. XLIX, No. 2, 1985 November; MacCreadyPB_04_01_007_08 (Box 4.7, Folder 8)
    - Art and nature in the technology of flight, Leonardo Vol. 19, No. 4, 1986; MacCreadyPB_04_01_007_09 (Box 4.7, Folder 9)
    - Biological flight, mechanical flight, and efficient transportation, Journal of the Washington Academy of Sciences Vol. 76, No. 1, 1986 March; MacCreadyPB_04_01_007_10 (Box 4.7, Folder 10)
    - Muscle-powered flight, Third International Human Powered Vehicle Scientific Symposium prodeedings, 1986 August 28-29; MacCreadyPB_04_01_007_11 (Box 4.7, Folder 11)
    - Light aircraft in the early 21st century; Wings for fun, The Smithsonian book of flight ( by Walter. J. Boyne), 1987; MacCreadyPB_04_01_007_12 (Box 4.7, Folder 12)
    - An evolutionary perspective, Free Inquiry, 1987 Spring; MacCreadyPB_04_01_007_13 (Box 4.7, Folder 13)
    - Of birds, bees, and airplanes, IEEE Potentials Vol. 6, No. 2, 1987 May; MacCreadyPB_04_01_007_14 (Box 4.7, Folder 14)
    - Goals, rules and technological innovation, Human Power Vol. 6, No. 2, 1987 Summer; MacCreadyPB_04_01_007_15 (Box 4.7, Folder 15)
    - Technology, in perspective and under control, Engineering & Science Vol. LI, No. 1, 1987 Fall; MacCreadyPB_04_01_007_16 (Box 4.7, Folder 16)
    - Natural and artificial flying machines, Perspectives in fluid mechanics, 1988; MacCreadyPB_04_01_007_17 (Box 4.7, Folder 17)
    - Flying wing boomerangs into favor (Letters to the Times), Los Angeles Times, 1988 July 30; MacCreadyPB_04_01_007_18 (Box 4.7, Folder 18)
    - Seventy-five reasons to become a scientist, American Scientist Vol. 76, No. 5, 1988 September-October; MacCreadyPB_04_01_007_19 (Box 4.7, Folder 19)
    - Perspectives about some major issues, Lament Vol. XXVI, No. 2, 1989 February; MacCreadyPB_04_01_008_01 (Box 4.8, Folder 1)
    - Lessons of Sunraycer, American Scientist Vol. 260, No. 3, 1989 March; MacCreadyPB_04_01_008_02 (Box 4.8, Folder 2)
    - Perspectives in transportation, JAPCA Vol. 39, No. 11, 1989 November; MacCreadyPB_04_01_008_03 (Box 4.8, Folder 3)
    - Inventing the nineties, Playboy, 1990 January; MacCreadyPB_04_01_008_04 (Box 4.8, Folder 4)
    - Tommy Asks, 1990 January 5; MacCreadyPB_04_01_008_05 (Box 4.8, Folder 5)
    - The future of human-powered vehicles, HPV News Vol. 6, No. 4, 1990 January-February; MacCreadyPB_04_01_008_06 (Box 4.8, Folder 6)
    - Gossamer aircraft and where they lead, 1990 February; MacCreadyPB_04_01_008_07 (Box 4.8, Folder 7)
    - A jaundiced look at graphology, Insight Vol. 6, No. 9, 1990 February; MacCreadyPB_04_01_008_08 (Box 4.8, Folder 8)
    - On a wing and a dinosaur, Omni, 1990 May; MacCreadyPB_04_01_008_09 (Box 4.8, Folder 9)
    - Saving other species, L.A. Times, 1990 May 13; MacCreadyPB_04_01_008_10 (Box 4.8, Folder 10)
    - Vehicle efficiency and the electric option, Transportation and Global Climate Change, 1991; MacCreadyPB_04_01_008_11 (Box 4.8, Folder 11)
    - Nature and technology: seeking a balance, Australian Geographic No. 23, 1991 July-September; MacCreadyPB_04_01_008_12 (Box 4.8, Folder 12)
    - Contemplating the unexpected, Engineering & Science Vol. LV, No. 3, 1992 Spring; MacCreadyPB_04_01_008_13 (Box 4.8, Folder 13)
    - Design, efficiency, and the peacock's tail, Automative Engineering, 1992 October; MacCreadyPB_04_01_008_14 (Box 4.8, Folder 14)
    - Perspectives on vehicle energy efficiency and electric vehicles, ESD Technology, 1992 November; MacCreadyPB_04_01_008_15 (Box 4.8, Folder 15)
    - Foreword, Solar Racing Cars: 1993 World Solar Challenge, MacCreadyPB_04_01_008_16 (Box 4.8, Folder 16)
    - Teaching elementary science with toys: introduction, 1993; MacCreadyPB_04_01_008_17 (Box 4.8, Folder 17)
    - Potential and achievement: Categorization of genius, Skeptic Vol. 2, No. 1, 1993; MacCreadyPB_04_01_008_18 (Box 4.8, Folder 18)
    - A Declaration of Interdependence, 1993 December 20; MacCreadyPB_04_01_008_19 (Box 4.8, Folder 19)
    - Reflections on birthday books, 1993 December 30; MacCreadyPB_04_01_008_20 (Box 4.8, Folder 20)
    - Considering the 2 per cent in 98 mandate, 1994 January 10; MacCreadyPB_04_01_008_21 (Box 4.8, Folder 21)
    - Is a lion in a zoo a real lion?, 1994 April 9; MacCreadyPB_04_01_008_22 (Box 4.8, Folder 22)
    - Why bother?, 1994 April 10; MacCreadyPB_04_01_008_23 (Box 4.8, Folder 23)
    - Doing more with much less, Inventor-Assistance Program news No. 36, 1994 May; MacCreadyPB_04_01_008_24 (Box 4.8, Folder 24)
    - Electric vehicle challenges and opportunities, 1994 May 11; MacCreadyPB_04_01_008_25 (Box 4.8, Folder 25)
    - Battery Electric Vehicles (BEVs), 1994 September 30; MacCreadyPB_04_01_008_26 (Box 4.8, Folder 26)
    - Protecting the White House, 1994 November 10; MacCreadyPB_04_01_008_27 (Box 4.8, Folder 27)
    - Gossamer aircraft and where they lead; and The value and future of human-powered vehicles, Human-powered vehicles, 1995; MacCreadyPB_04_01_008_28 (Box 4.8, Folder 28)
    - Views on transportation policy; and Perspectives on vehicle energy efficiency and electric vehicles Building the E-motive industry, 1995; MacCreadyPB_04_01_008_29 (Box 4.8, Folder 29)
    - Hamster Airplane Project: mid course review and plan, 1995 February 6; MacCreadyPB_04_01_008_30 (Box 4.8, Folder 30)
    - Musing on mandates, 1995 April 9; MacCreadyPB_04_01_008_31 (Box 4.8, Folder 31)
    - Hamster glider power, 1995 May; MacCreadyPB_04_01_008_32 (Box 4.8, Folder 32)
    - Atmospheric talents, Bulletin of the American Meteorological Society Vol. 76, No. 6, 1995 June; MacCreadyPB_04_01_008_33 (Box 4.8, Folder 33)
    - Perspectives and prejudices about some major issues, Leonardo Vol. 28, No. 2, 1995 July; MacCreadyPB_04_01_008_34 (Box 4.8, Folder 34)
    - Getting power from an animal, 1995 November 27; MacCreadyPB_04_01_008_35 (Box 4.8, Folder 35)
    - Design in 2046, Design News, 1996 November 4; MacCreadyPB_04_01_008_36 (Box 4.8, Folder 36)
    - The inventive process, Design Outlaws on the Ecological Frontier. Executive editor Chris Zelov, Co-Editor Phil Cousineau, 1997; MacCreadyPB_04_01_008_37 (Box 4.8, Folder 37)
    - A story of biological and technological computation, 1998 October 31; MacCreadyPB_04_01_008_38 (Box 4.8, Folder 38)
    - The next 35 years of engineering computing, 1999; MacCreadyPB_04_01_008_39 (Box 4.8, Folder 39)
    - An ambivalent luddite at a technological feast, Designfax Vol. 21, No. 8, 1999 August; MacCreadyPB_04_01_008_40 (Box 4.8, Folder 40)
    - Becoming a birdbrain: Airborne video for radio controlled sailplanes, Sailplane & Electric Modeler, 1999 August-September; MacCreadyPB_04_01_008_41 (Box 4.8, Folder 41)
    - Letter to the editor TWITT Newsletter, 1999 October; MacCreadyPB_04_01_008_42 (Box 4.8, Folder 42)
    - Pursuing soaring visions Soaring, 2000 February; MacCreadyPB_04_01_008_43 (Box 4.8, Folder 43)
    - Book introduction, Wind and wings, the history of soaring in San Diego, 1883-1950, 2000 April 25; MacCreadyPB_04_01_008_44 (Box 4.8, Folder 44)
    - What will cars be like in 25 years? Popular Science, 2000 May; MacCreadyPB_04_01_008_45 (Box 4.8, Folder 45)
    - Squeezing past history, Air & Space, 2000 December- 2001 January; MacCreadyPB_04_01_008_46 (Box 4.8, Folder 46)
    - Seen invisible: the underpinning of flight, AND Unoccupied air vehicles: how far can we go? Aviation 100 Vol. 2, 2001; MacCreadyPB_04_01_008_47 (Box 4.8, Folder 47)
    - Revisiting Tommy Asks, 2001 August 17; MacCreadyPB_04_01_008_48 (Box 4.8, Folder 48)
    - Speculations about goals and challenges in a millenium of space ventures, 1991; MacCreadyPB_04_01_010_15 (Box 4.10, Folder 15)
  - Talks, 2
    - Oxygen equipment and use, South Cotswold Soaring Association, 1950; MacCreadyPB_04_02_009_01 (Box 4.9, Folder 1)
    - 1950s Talks, 1950-1960; MacCreadyPB_04_02_009_02 (Box 4.9, Folder 2)
    - Munitalp Foundation Talks, 1955-1956; MacCreadyPB_04_02_009_03 (Box 4.9, Folder 3)
    - 1960s talks, MacCreadyPB_04_02_009_04 (Box 4.9, Folder 4)
    - Droplet distribution and precipitation mechanisms in a particular cloud system, International conference on Cloud Physics (Japan), 1965 May-June; MacCreadyPB_04_02_009_05 (Box 4.9, Folder 5)
    - Instruments and techniques for locating and exploiting thermals, OSTIV Congress (Alpine, TX), 1970 July; MacCreadyPB_04_02_009_06 (Box 4.9, Folder 6)
    - Micrometeorology and hang gliding, US Hang Gliding Association (CA), 1974 November 18; MacCreadyPB_04_02_009_07 (Box 4.9, Folder 7)
    - Engineering flight test program of Gossamer Condor, The Society of Experimental Test Pilots, 1977 September-October; MacCreadyPB_04_02_009_08 (Box 4.9, Folder 8)
    - Man-powered flight and Gossamer Condor, Australian Division of the Royal Aeronautical Society, 1978 February 15; MacCreadyPB_04_02_009_09 (Box 4.9, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous conference and lecture materials, 1978 - 2000; MacCreadyPB_04_02_009_10 (Box 4.9, Folder 10)
    - Gossamer presentation at IBM Corporate Recognition Event (New York), 1980 April 22; MacCreadyPB_04_02_009_11 (Box 4.9, Folder 11)
    - Gossamer aircraft and where they lead, Worcester Polytechnic Institute Commencement Address, 1980 May 31; MacCreadyPB_04_02_009_12 (Box 4.9, Folder 12)
    - Remarks by Paul MacCready at the Solar Challenger press conference, 1980 June 5; MacCreadyPB_04_02_009_13 (Box 4.9, Folder 13)
    - Impractical aircraft, practical dreams, ca. 1981-1982; MacCreadyPB_04_02_009_14 (Box 4.9, Folder 14)
    - Gossamer aircraft and creativity, Presentations for IBM (Miami, FL), 1982 April 3; 6; MacCreadyPB_04_02_009_15 (Box 4.9, Folder 15)
    - Commencement '82 49er Engineer, California State University Long Beach, 1982 Spring; MacCreadyPB_04_02_009_16 (Box 4.9, Folder 16)
    - Remarks at Lindbergh Awards dinner (St. Louis, MO), 1982 May 22; MacCreadyPB_04_02_009_17 (Box 4.9, Folder 17)
    - Flight on sunbeams - Meeting the challenge, Solar Energy Society (Houston, TX), 1982 June 3-4; MacCreadyPB_04_02_009_18 (Box 4.9, Folder 18)
    - Wind energy for China (China), 1984 November; MacCreadyPB_04_02_009_19 (Box 4.9, Folder 19)
    - The giant pterodactyl project for 'On the wing', Space Science Center (Edmonton, Canada), 1985 September 19-21; MacCreadyPB_04_02_009_20 (Box 4.9, Folder 20)
    - The great pterodactyl project, Caltech Y presentation (Pasadena, CA), 1985 October 6; MacCreadyPB_04_02_009_21 (Box 4.9, Folder 21)
    - Biological flight, mechanical flight and efficient transportation, The Lindbergh Symposium (Epcot Center, FL), 1986 February 3-4; MacCreadyPB_04_02_010_01 (Box 4.10, Folder 1)
    - Motivation for innovation: Interactions between goals, rules, technology and economics, World Congress on the Medical and Scientific Aspects of Cycling (Colorado Springs, CO), 1986 September 2-3; MacCreadyPB_04_02_010_02 (Box 4.10, Folder 2)
    - Innovation by nature and man, Steelcase Corporation (Grand Rapids, MI), 1987 March 25; MacCreadyPB_04_02_010_03 (Box 4.10, Folder 3)
    - Keynote address - Exploring the human future: prospects for a better balance, Lindbergh Fund Grants Reunion (Little Falls, MN), 1987 June 19-21; MacCreadyPB_04_02_010_04 (Box 4.10, Folder 4)
    - Aerodynamics of low-powered vehicles, National Soaring Convention (Los Angeles, CA), 1988 August; MacCreadyPB_04_02_010_05 (Box 4.10, Folder 5)
    - The Gell-Mann approach, and thoughts on the human future, Murray Gell-Mann 60th birthday symposium, 1989 January 28; MacCreadyPB_04_02_010_06 (Box 4.10, Folder 6)
    - Nature/technology balance and thinking skills education, Lindbergh Fund Talk (Princeton, NJ), 1989 April 29; MacCreadyPB_04_02_010_07 (Box 4.10, Folder 7)
    - The future is now, Air and Waste Management Association (Anaheim, CA), 1989 June 26; MacCreadyPB_04_02_010_08 (Box 4.10, Folder 8)
    - The future of human powered vehicles, International Human Powered Vehicle Association(Adrian, MI), 1989 September 16; MacCreadyPB_04_02_010_09 (Box 4.10, Folder 9)
    - A plan for exploring flight; Further comments on the exploring flight wing; Comments on the Museum of Flying theme piece; The Solar Challenger, Science Museum of Virginia (Richmond, VA), 1989-1992; MacCreadyPB_04_02_010_10 (Box 4.10, Folder 10)
    - Specualtions about goals and challenges in a millenium of space ventures; panel discussion, Vision -21: Space Travel for the Next Millenium, NASA, 1990 April 3 -4; MacCreadyPB_04_02_010_11 (Box 4.10, Folder 11)
    - Introduction to On the wing, Science World (Vancouver, BC), 1990 May 2; MacCreadyPB_04_02_010_12 (Box 4.10, Folder 12)
    - Comments as Master of Ceremonies, Lindbergh Award Presentation (New York, NY), 1990 May 15; MacCreadyPB_04_02_010_13 (Box 4.10, Folder 13)
    - Reconciliation of environment and technology; Electric vehicles and environment, Workshop on Environmental Science and Technology (Hong Kong), 1990 September 17-21; MacCreadyPB_04_02_010_14 (Box 4.10, Folder 14)
    - Comments as Master of Ceremonies, Lindbergh Award Presentation (New York, NY), 1991 May 7; MacCreadyPB_04_02_010_16 (Box 4.10, Folder 16)
    - Further than you might think, Transportation and Global Climate Changes (Asilomar, CA), 1991 August 26; MacCreadyPB_04_02_010_17 (Box 4.10, Folder 17)
    - The value and future of human powered vehicles, Fourth International Human Powered Vehicle Scientific Symposium (Yreka, CA), 1992 August 6; MacCreadyPB_04_02_010_18 (Box 4.10, Folder 18)
    - Development of unorthodox vehicles, GE PRICE User Symposium (Manhattan Beach, CA), 1993 March 17; MacCreadyPB_04_02_010_19 (Box 4.10, Folder 19)
    - Comments as Master of Ceremonies, Lindbergh Award Presentation (New York, NY), 1993 May 26; MacCreadyPB_04_02_010_20 (Box 4.10, Folder 20)
    - Exploring the concept of a Demand Energy Supply Corp, Talk for Delco Remy, 1993 June 16; MacCreadyPB_04_02_010_21 (Box 4.10, Folder 21)
    - Future transportation growth in a constrained environment, World Car Conference (Riverside, CA), 1993 June 21; MacCreadyPB_04_02_010_22 (Box 4.10, Folder 22)
    - Statement, field hearing for green technologies for societal benefit, 1993 August 18; MacCreadyPB_04_02_010_23 (Box 4.10, Folder 23)
    - Lightweight construction and aerodynamics, Conference on Electric Hybrids (Zurich), 1993 September 20; MacCreadyPB_04_02_010_24 (Box 4.10, Folder 24)
    - Environmental Business '93, Environment 2000 - the future of the industry, 1993 October 26; MacCreadyPB_04_02_010_25 (Box 4.10, Folder 25)
    - Doing More with Less, Keynote talk, Hawaii EV '93, 1993 December 9; MacCreadyPB_04_02_010_26 (Box 4.10, Folder 26)
    - Small and electric: Vehicles with a future, Meeting of the Transportation Research Board (Washington, DC), 1994 January 13; MacCreadyPB_04_02_011_01 (Box 4.11, Folder 1)
    - What is NEV? Neighborhood Electric Vehicle Workshop (Davis, CA), 1994 June 30; MacCreadyPB_04_02_011_02 (Box 4.11, Folder 2)
    - The evolution of efficient mobility, Dedicated conference on supercars (Aachen, GE), 1994 October 31; MacCreadyPB_04_02_011_03 (Box 4.11, Folder 3)
    - Doing more with less, Ecological Design, 1995 January; MacCreadyPB_04_02_011_04 (Box 4.11, Folder 4)
    - Atmospheric talents (The atmosphere for efficiency), American Meteorlogical Society (Dallas, TX), 1995 January 17; MacCreadyPB_04_02_011_05 (Box 4.11, Folder 5)
    - Innovation in spite of education and organization, Presentation at GM, 1995 February 16; MacCreadyPB_04_02_011_06 (Box 4.11, Folder 6)
    - Essential elements of future transportation technology, Presentation to Task Force on Strategic Energy R and D (Washington, DC), 1995 February 28; MacCreadyPB_04_02_011_07 (Box 4.11, Folder 7)
    - Comments on innovation/invention, Lemelson-MIT Prize Event (Washington, DC), 1995 March 29; MacCreadyPB_04_02_011_08 (Box 4.11, Folder 8)
    - Keynote address, International Conference on Alternative Aviation Fuels, Baylor University (Waco, TX), 1995 November 2; MacCreadyPB_04_02_011_09 (Box 4.11, Folder 9)
    - Unleashing creativity, Symposium on the Inventor and the Innovative Society (Washington, DC), 1995 November 10; MacCreadyPB_04_02_011_10 (Box 4.11, Folder 10)
    - Follow-up to presentation by Paul MacCready at the E-Source Managers Round Table (Houston, TX), 1997 April 16; MacCreadyPB_04_02_011_11 (Box 4.11, Folder 11)
    - Comments as Master of Ceremonies, Lindbergh Award Presentation (Air Force Academy, CO), 1997 May 10; MacCreadyPB_04_02_011_12 (Box 4.11, Folder 12)
    - Video presentation for Innovation 97, MICA Management Resources (Toronto, Ontario), 1997 May 29; MacCreadyPB_04_02_011_13 (Box 4.11, Folder 13)
    - The best half century so far, Yale Class of 1947, Fiftieth Reunion (Ithaca, NY), 1997 May 31; MacCreadyPB_04_02_011_14 (Box 4.11, Folder 14)
    - Preparing for your exploration of the future, commencement address, Cal Poly Pomona (Pomona, CA), 1997 June 12; MacCreadyPB_04_02_011_15 (Box 4.11, Folder 15)
    - The future of environmental technology, Symposium on Exploring New Technologies for Clean Air (Beckman Center, Irvine, CA), 1997 September 29; MacCreadyPB_04_02_011_16 (Box 4.11, Folder 16)
    - People and Technology, Multimedia Roundtable (Yale), 1998; April 1; MacCreadyPB_04_02_011_17 (Box 4.11, Folder 17)
    - Human Powered Flight, 28th Lester D. Gardner Lecture, MIT (Boston, MA), 1998 April 27; MacCreadyPB_04_02_011_18 (Box 4.11, Folder 18)
    - Comments as Master of Ceremonies, Lindbergh Award Presentation (New York, NY), 1998 May 20; MacCreadyPB_04_02_011_19 (Box 4.11, Folder 19)
    - Regenerative battery-augmented soaring, Self Launching Sailplane Symposium (Elmira, NY), 1998 July 16; MacCreadyPB_04_02_011_20 (Box 4.11, Folder 20)
    - "Micro Airplanes," Things that think, see, feel and do (Los Angeles, CA), 1998 November 10-11; MacCreadyPB_04_02_011_21 (Box 4.11, Folder 21)
    - "The excitement and value of engineering," ASME Ralph Coats Lecture (Anaheim, CA), 1998 November 19; MacCreadyPB_04_02_011_22 (Box 4.11, Folder 22)
    - "Ubiquitous charging of electric vehicles," NAEVI presentation (Phoenix, AZ), 1998 December 3; MacCreadyPB_04_02_011_23 (Box 4.11, Folder 23)
    - "Raspet as mentor and pioneer," Raspet Lab 50th Anniversary (Starkville, MS), 1999 February 24; MacCreadyPB_04_02_011_24 (Box 4.11, Folder 24)
    - "Soaring: Addictions and perspectives," SSA Soaring Convention (Knoxville, TN), 1999 February 27; MacCreadyPB_04_02_011_25 (Box 4.11, Folder 25)
    - "An ambivalent luddite at a technological feast," CTI Roundtable '99, 1999 April 12-14; MacCreadyPB_04_02_011_26 (Box 4.11, Folder 26)
    - "Transportation/Mobility vs increasing population and energy consumption," Modern transport in Hong Kong for the 21st century, 1999 May 1; MacCreadyPB_04_02_012_01 (Box 4.12, Folder 1)
    - Comments as Master of Ceremonies, Lindbergh Award Presentation (New York, NY), 1999 May 18; MacCreadyPB_04_02_012_02 (Box 4.12, Folder 2)
    - "Structural challenges for wing spans from 6 Inches to 250 feet," Materials, Manufacturing and Enabling Technologies Series, 1999 July 21; MacCreadyPB_04_02_012_03 (Box 4.12, Folder 3)
    - "Technalegs that carry your backpack," DARPA Workshop, 2000 March 1 - 3; MacCreadyPB_04_02_012_04 (Box 4.12, Folder 4)
    - "Educating for the student's 25th birthday," TechEd 2000 (Palm Springs, CA), 2000 March 7; MacCreadyPB_04_02_012_05 (Box 4.12, Folder 5)
    - Comments as Master of Ceremonies, Lindbergh Award Presentation (Seattle, WA), 2000 May 20; MacCreadyPB_04_02_012_06 (Box 4.12, Folder 6)
    - Presentation to UCAR (University Cooperation for Atmospheric Research) Forty (Boulder, CO), 2000 October 10; MacCreadyPB_04_02_012_07 (Box 4.12, Folder 7)
    - "Revolutionary vs. evolutionary strategies for energy," 2000 Fuel Cell Seminar (Portland, OR), 2000 November 1; MacCreadyPB_04_02_012_08 (Box 4.12, Folder 8)
    - "Improving fuel efficiency of weapons platforms," Presentation to the Defense Science Board Task Force (Washington, DC), 2000 November 18; MacCreadyPB_04_02_012_09 (Box 4.12, Folder 9)
    - "The Telepresence Real Simulator," BEES 2000 (Pasadena, CA), 2000 December 5; MacCreadyPB_04_02_012_10 (Box 4.12, Folder 10)
    - "An Ambivalent luddite in a technological kitchen," TED 11 (Monterey, CA), 2001 February 22; MacCreadyPB_04_02_012_11 (Box 4.12, Folder 11)
    - "Unleashing and assimilating innovation for/from aerospace," Looking forward: Is innovation dead?" (Lake Buena Vista, FL), 2001 March 15; MacCreadyPB_04_02_012_12 (Box 4.12, Folder 12)
    - Purdue School of Engineering and Technology commencement, 2002 May 11; MacCreadyPB_04_02_012_13 (Box 4.12, Folder 13)
    - "Aerodynamics and other efficiencies in transporting goods," The Aerodynamics of Heavy Vehicles (Monterey, CA), 2002 December 2-6; MacCreadyPB_04_02_012_14 (Box 4.12, Folder 14)
- Biographical and Correspondence, 5
  - Correspondence, 1
    - Correspondence, 1943 April-1944 February; MacCreadyPB_05_01_001_01 (Box 5.1, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1944 March 6-22; MacCreadyPB_05_01_001_02 (Box 5.1, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1944 March 23-31; MacCreadyPB_05_01_001_03 (Box 5.1, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1944 April 1-13; MacCreadyPB_05_01_001_04 (Box 5.1, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1944 April 16-28; MacCreadyPB_05_01_001_05 (Box 5.1, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1944 May 1-16; MacCreadyPB_05_01_001_06 (Box 5.1, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1944 May 16-31; MacCreadyPB_05_01_002_01 (Box 5.2, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1944 May 30; MacCreadyPB_05_01_002_02 (Box 5.2, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1944 June; MacCreadyPB_05_01_002_03 (Box 5.2, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1944 July; MacCreadyPB_05_01_002_04 (Box 5.2, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1944 August 2 - September 12; MacCreadyPB_05_01_002_05 (Box 5.2, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1944 October; MacCreadyPB_05_01_002_06 (Box 5.2, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1944 November; MacCreadyPB_05_01_002_07 (Box 5.2, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1944 December; MacCreadyPB_05_01_002_08 (Box 5.2, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1944 December - 1945 January; MacCreadyPB_05_01_002_09 (Box 5.2, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1945 February; MacCreadyPB_05_01_002_10 (Box 5.2, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1945 March; MacCreadyPB_05_01_003_01 (Box 5.3, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1945 April 2 - 16; MacCreadyPB_05_01_003_02 (Box 5.3, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1945 April 17 - 30; MacCreadyPB_05_01_003_03 (Box 5.3, Folder 3)